and we can see it in this first slide. (Laughter) (Applause) Immediately your processing goes to, "Is that a hard-boiled egg?" (Laughter) "Is that perhaps the structural integrity of the egg being able to sustain the weight of what seems to be a rock? Aha, is it in fact a real rock?" We go to questions when we see visual information. But when we hear information, this is what happens. (Laughter) The floodgates in our mind open much like the streets of Shanghai. (Applause) So many pieces of information to process, so many ideas, concepts, feelings and, of course, vulnerabilities
y lo podemos ver en la primera diapositiva. (Risas) (Aplausos) Inmediatamente tu razonamiento es "¿es ese un huevo cocido?" (Risas) "¿Es acaso la estructura integral de un huevo que es capaz de soportar el peso de lo que parece ser una roca? Ajá ¿es de hecho una roca de verdad?". Nos hacemos preguntas cuando tenemos información visual, pero cuando escuchamos información esto es lo que pasa. (Risas) Las compuertas de nuestra mente se abren tanto como las calles de Shanghái. (Aplausos) Mucha información por procesar, tantas ideas, conceptos, sentimientos y por supuesto vulnerabilidades,
that we don't often wish to share. And so we hide,
que por lo regular no deseamos compartir. Por eso nos escondemos
and we hide behind what we like to call the floodgate of intimacy. (Laughter) And what might that floodgate be holding? What is the dike upon which it is built? Well, first off -- (Laughter) we found that it's different for six different genotypes. (Applause) And, of course, we can start categorizing these genotypes into a neuronormative experience and a neurodiverse experience.
y nos ocultamos detrás de lo que conocemos como las compuertas de la intimidad. (Risas) ¿Y qué será lo que esas compuertas sostienen? ¿Cuál será la presa sobre la que se construyó? Bueno, primero que nada... (Risas) Encontramos que es diferente para seis genotipos distintos . (Aplausos) Por supuesto, podemos empezar por clasificar estos genotipos como experiencias neuronormativas y experiencias neurodiversas.
(Laughter) On the right-hand side of the screen,
(Risas) Del lado derecho de la pantalla
you're seeing spikes for the neurodiverse thinking. Now, there are generally only two emotional states that a neurodiverse brain can tabulate and keep count of at any given time, thereby eliminating the possibility for them to be emotionally, sometimes, attuned to the present situation. But on the left-hand side, you can see the neuronormative brain, which can often handle about five different pieces of emotional cognitive information at any given time. These are the slight variances that you are seeing in the 75, 90 and 60 percentile,
notarán los incrementos en la forma de pensar neurodiversa. Por lo general, hay solo dos estados emocionales que un cerebro neurodiverso puede tabular y registrar en cualquier momento. De este modo se elimina la posibilidad de que ellos se sientan, en ocasiones, emocionalmente conectados con la situación del momento. Pero en el lado izquierdo, pueden ver un cerebro neuronormativo que puede manejar cerca de cinco tipos diferentes de información cognitiva emocional en cualquier momento. Estos son las pequeñas variaciones que observan en los 75, 90 y 60 %.
and then of course that dramatic difference of the 25, 40 and 35 percentile. (Laughter) But of course, what is the neural network that is helping to bridge and build these different discrepancies? (Laughter) Fear. (Applause) And as we all know, fear resides in the amygdala, and it is a very natural response, and it is very closely linked with visual perception. It is not as closely linked with verbal perception, so our fear receptors often will be going off in advance of any of our cognitive usage around verbal and words and cues of language. So as we see these fear moments, we of course are taken aback. We stumble in a certain direction, generally away from the intimacy. (Laughter) Now of course, there's a difference between the male perception and the female perception and of trans and those who are in between, all of those as well,
y, por supuesto, la dramática diferencia de 25, 40 y 35 %. (Risas) Pero ¿cuál es la red neuronal que ayuda a generar estas diferentes discrepancias? (Risas) El miedo. (Aplausos) Como todos sabemos, el miedo reside en la amígdala. Es una respuesta natural y se encuentra muy conectada con la percepción visual. No se encuentra tan conectada con la percepción verbal, así que con frecuencia nuestros receptores del miedo se apagarán con antelación ante cualquier uso cognitivo de las palabras y señales del idioma. Estos momentos de miedo nos dejan desconcertados. Vacilamos hacia cierta dirección, por lo general, lejos de la intimidad. (Risas) Es claro que hay diferencias entre la percepción masculina y la percepción femenina, y de los trans y aquellos que están en medio,
and outside of the gender spectrum. (Laughter) But fear is the central underlying underpinning of all of our response systems. Fight-or-flight is one of the earliest, some say reptilian, response to our environment. How can we disengage or unhook ourselves from the horns of the amygdala? (Laughter) Well, I'd like to tell you the secret right now. (Applause) This is all making much, much too much sense. (Laughter) The secret lies in turning our backs to one another, and I know that that sounds absolutely like the opposite of what you were expecting, but when in a relationship you turn your back to your partner and place your back upon their back -- (Laughter)
y fuera del espectro de género. (Risas) El miedo es la parte básica principal de todos nuestros sistemas de respuesta. "Pelear o huir" es una de las primeras, algunos dicen reptiliano, respuestas al entorno. ¿Cómo podemos desprendernos o desengancharnos de la amígdala? (Risas) Me gustaría compartir ahora con Uds. el secreto. (Aplausos) Todo esto tiene mucho, mucho sentido. (Risas) El secreto recae en darnos la espalda unos a otros. Sé que esto suena totalmente contradictorio a lo que esperaban, pero cuando en una relación le das la espalda a tu pareja y pones tu espalda sobre la de ellos... (Risas)
you eliminate visual cues. (Applause) You are more readily available to failing first, and failing first -- (Laughter) far outweighs the lengths we go to to appeal to others, to our partners and to ourselves. We spend billions and billions of dollars on clothing, on makeup, on the latest trend of glasses, but what we don't spend money and time on is connecting with each other in a way that is truthful and honest
se eliminan los indicadores visuales. (Aplausos) Estarán más preparados a fracasar primero, y al fracasar primero... (Risas) supera con creces a lo que somos capaces de hacer para agradar a los demás, a nuestras parejas y a nosotros mismos. Gastamos miles de millones de dólares en ropa, maquillaje, en los lentes que están de moda, pero no invertimos tiempo y dinero en conectarnos con los demás de una manera verdadera y honesta
and stripped of those visual receptors. (Applause) (Laughter) It sounds hard, doesn't it? But we want to be aggressive about this. We don't want to just sit on the couch. As a historian said earlier today, it's important to get up and circumvent sometimes that couch.
y sin la necesidad de esos receptores visuales. (Aplausos) (Risas) ¿Parece difícil, no? Queremos ser determinantes sobre esto. No queremos dormirnos en nuestros laureles. Hoy temprano un historiador mencionó que es importante levantarse y en ocasiones eludir esos problemas.
And how can we do it? Well yes, ice is a big part of it. Insights, compassion and empathy: I, C, E. (Applause) And when we start using this ice method, well, the possibilities become much bigger than us. In fact, they become smaller than you. On a molecular level, I believe that that insight
¿Cómo lo podemos lograr? El "ice" es una gran parte de eso. Intuición, compasión y empatía I, C, E. (Aplausos) Cuando empezamos a utilizar el método "ice", las posibilidades se tornan más grandes que nosotros. De hecho, se hacen más pequeñas que Uds. A un nivel molecular creo que esa visión
is the unifying theme for every talk you have seen so far at TED and will continue as we of course embark on this journey here on this tiny planet, on the ledge, on the precipice, as we are seeing, yes, death is inevitable. (Laughter) Will it meet all of us at the same time, I think, is the variable we are inquiring. (Laughter) I think that timeline gets a bit longer when we use ice and when we rest our backs upon one another and build together, leaving behind the fear and working towards -- (Laughter) they'll edit this part out -- a ripened experience of love, compassion, intimacy based on a truth that you are sharing from your mind's eye and the heart that we all can touch, tactilely feel, have maybe potentially a mushy experience that we don't just throw out because it is browned, but let us slice in half the experience we have gathered, let us seed what the heart, the core, the seed of that idea in each of us is, and let us share it back to back. Thank you very much. (Applause)
es el tema unificador para cada charla que han visto en TED, y continuaremos con el curso de este viaje aquí en este pequeño planeta, en la cornisa, en el precipicio, tal como lo vemos, sí, la muerte es inevitable. (Risas) ¿Nos llegará a todos al mismo tiempo? Creo es la variable a nuestra interrogante. (Risas) Me parece que esa línea del tiempo se alargará un poco más si aplicamos "ice", nos apoyamos sobre las espaldas de los demás y construimos juntos, dejando de lado el miedo y trabajando hacia... (Risas) ellos borrarán esta parte... una experiencia madura de amor, de compasión, de intimidad basada en una verdad que Uds. comparten desde los ojos de la mente y el corazón que todos somos capaces de tocar, de sentir táctilmente, y tener una experiencia sentimental apabullante, y que no la desechamos tan solo porque se ha oscurecido, pero que nos permita dividir la experiencia que acumulamos, que nos permita plantar en el corazón, el centro, la semilla de esa idea en cada uno de nosotros y compartirla entre nosotros. Muchas gracias. (Aplausos)